<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Greetings, I'm Miguel 👋 on Miguel Villa Floran</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/</link><description>Recent content in Greetings, I'm Miguel 👋 on Miguel Villa Floran</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://miguelvf.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An Easy Guide to Using Tmux</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/dotfiles/tmux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/dotfiles/tmux/</guid><description>Tmux# Usage# Install tmux
sudo apt install tmux Install tpm (Tmux Plugin Manager)
git clone https://github.com/tmux-plugins/tpm ~/.tmux/plugins/tpm Reload TMUX environment so TPM is sourced:
# type this in terminal if tmux is already running tmux source $XDG_CONFIG_HOME/tmux/tmux.conf Keybinds# To enter commands into tmux, you must enter a specific keybind, which is called the prefix key, followed by the command. My prefix key is ctrl + space.
To refresh tmux and install new plugins, type prefix + I (capital i, as in Install)</description></item><item><title>Crafting a Robust and Maintainable C Makefile</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/c-makefile/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/c-makefile/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty pedantic about the quality of my code, and I like to keep my projects organized and maintainable. One of the tools that I use to achieve this is GNU Make, which is a powerful build system that can be used to automate the process of compiling and linking C programs. In this post, I will show you how to create a simple and robust Makefile template that can be used in your C projects.</description></item><item><title>Using Secure Shell (ssh) and Key-Based Authentication</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/dotfiles/ssh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/dotfiles/ssh/</guid><description>Installation# An ssh client is required to connect to remote servers. Fortunately, ssh is already installed on most Linux distributions and macOS. As of Windows 10, OpenSSH is included in Windows. To check whether you have it installed, run the following command:
ssh -V If ssh is not installed on your machine, you can install it by running the following command:
sudo apt-get install openssh-client openssh-server Usage# Once ssh is installed on your machine, you can connect to remote servers and interface with them via the commands line.</description></item><item><title>The Things I Use</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/uses/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/uses/</guid><description>Getting closer to how your environment actualy works will only expand your mind — Michael B. Paulson, otherwise known as ThePrimeagen
This page was last edited on March 29, 2024
My former college roomate and good friend, Hayden Buscher, recently made a post about the things he uses to stay productive. Giving credit where its due, I thought it was a great idea, so I decided to give my own spin on it.</description></item><item><title>Documentation with Sphinx and GitHub Actions the Right Way</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/sphinx-github-actions-docs-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/sphinx-github-actions-docs-guide/</guid><description>One of the things I value the most when it comes to when it comes to writing software I publish is its maintainability, from the obscure and simple bash scripts to the large and complex programing pillars packed with passion that are placed in my programming portfolio.
For most people, this is limited to writing consise comments in the codebases with the hope that they work once and never need to be touched again.</description></item><item><title>My Impossible List</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/impossible-list/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/impossible-list/</guid><description>We choose to go to the Moon. We choose to go to the Moon in this decade and do the other things, not because they are easy, but because they are hard; because that goal will serve to organize and measure the best of our energies and skills, because that challenge is one that we are willing to accept, one we are unwilling to postpone&amp;hellip; And, therefore, as we set sail we ask God&amp;rsquo;s blessing on the most hazardous and dangerous and greatest adventure on which man has ever embarked.</description></item><item><title>Off-By-One Errors and How to Avoid Them</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/off-by-one/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/off-by-one/</guid><description>When I was a beginner at programming, I would often find myself struggling with the implementation of for loops. The amount of times I would need to iterate through an array, dictionary, iterable, or any given data structure would always be one more or one less than I anticipated. As a result, I became quite familiar with the following error message:
IndexError: list index out of range I recently discovered this problem I dealt with had a name: the off-by-one error.</description></item><item><title>SystemVerilog Best Practices</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/hdl-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/hdl-best-practices/</guid><description>When I was a beginner at programming, I would often find myself struggling with the implementation of for loops. The amount of times I would need to iterate through an array, dictionary, iterable, or any given data structure would always be one more or one less than I anticipated. As a result, I became quite familiar with the following error message:
IndexError: list index out of range I recently discovered this problem I dealt with had a name: the off-by-one error.</description></item><item><title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/markdown-syntax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/blog/markdown-syntax/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo
content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS
in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://miguelvf.dev/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://miguelvf.dev/cv/</guid><description>Experience# CEO/President 2013-12-01 - 2014-12-01 Pied Piper — Awesome compression company Palo Alto, CA Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman Scores™ that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.
Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores Education# Information Technology (Bachelor) 2011-06-01 - 2014-01-01 University of Oklahoma 4.</description></item></channel></rss>